Abderrahman Lahiaouni

SUMMARY

"Research and development engineer, graduated from an engineering school, experience extends from IT consulting to research, relevant technical skills as well as communication skills acquired from working and traveling to different countries. Fast learner, excited to see new things, with a strong sense of commitment, fellowship and cheerfulness"

WORK EXPERIENCE

OCT 2023 - FEB 2024 (FT)

Semvox gmbh – Kirkel, Germany Senior DevOps engineer

As part of the DevOps team, I was involved in extending an internal tool that provides SBOM reports to customers from the source code, to do the same for images using a new api, taking on diverse responsibilities such as working with the api maker to respond to our use case, and coordinating with our cyber security expert for validation.

MAR 2020 - JUNE 2023 (FT)

Consistec engineering – Saarbruecken, Germany **Senior software engineer**

Worked on transforming a legacy infrastructure to enable fast development, testing and deployment through tools such as Ansible and Docker. In addition to working on developing and maintaining a monitoring CLI python tool for customer servers running our product, and making up-to-date documentation for existing rest-apis using OpenAPI.

DEC 2018 - DEC 2019 (FT)

INRIA- Lille, France

Research and development engineer - Spirals

The project aimed to make CPU and time consuming SAT jobs, deployable remotely on a grid. Docker Machine, Ansible and Kubernetes were used for the reservation, configuration, deployment, and orchestration, through a Go api, running behind a reverse proxy, and a VPN using Docker Compose. The service was made it usable through adapting existing JavaFx GUI.

 $MAI\ 2018-NOV\ 2018\ \ (FT)$

INRIA – Lille, France

Intern for Graduation Project – Spirals

As part of the spirals team, -particularly interested in introducing more automation in the adaptation mechanisms of software systems - I worked on a project focused on cloud storage, more specifically on load balancing and data replication aspects. The emphasis was on practical outcomes concerning data popularity, network traffic and available resources

 $JUL\ 2017-SEP\ 2017\ \ (FT)$

Algo Consulting group – Rabat, Morocco **Summer internship**

First experience in a professional environment. I worked on a customer survey mobile application. Been given 3 days to acquire basics of .NET, Xamarin.Forms and make a prototype of one of the views in the app, becaming part of the production team. Tasks involved writing logic and UI using C# and XAML (Mystery Shopper)

-

6

Married, 29yo

Türkismühler str 19 66113 Saarbrücken

Deutschland

+49 17 63 44 18 202

■ lahiaouni.abd@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/lahiaouni-abderrahman/

EDUCATION

2013 – 2018 Engineer degree

Software Engineering

National School of Applied Sciences

2012 baccalaureate

Department of Math Rahaly El Faroug High school

TECHNICAL SKILLS

FRAMEWORKS Spring boot, bootstrap

DEVOPS Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible

maven, jenkins, gradle

git, github, gitlab-ci, Azure Devops

Languages Java, Sql, c/c++

Python, c#

html5, css, PHP, JavaScript

os Debian, CentOS, Arch

Windows, OS X

DB PostgreSQL, Oracle, Mysql

CERTIFICATIONS Test driven development using

python, pytest, and mock

COMMUNICATION SKILLS

TALKS More Intelligent Web 3.0

Microservices and OOP principles

workshops .Net intro

The Blockchain

LANGUAGES Arabic - Native

French – Fluent English – Fluent German – Bi

PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES

Goal Oriented

I believe in action over long-winded discussions, listen to everyone's viewpoints then draw a judgment based on reached consensus to immediately act and achieve goals quickly and efficiently.

Passionate

I have been interested in computer sciences from an early age. Academic and professional experiences have cemented this interest into a passion. I greatly enjoy carrying out fundamental and technical aspects in IT with practical and useful applications.